

# ALEX IULIAN

Linkedin:

linkedin.com/in/alex-iulian-dev

Email:

contactalexfr@gmail.com

**Portofolio:** 

https://alexfolio.nl/

Frontend Developer with strong background in Tech Support, best when doing communication-driven roles. I bring 3+ years of experience in B2B SaaS environments, specializing in frontend development and user authentication. Natural at communicating tech to non-tech people and leading teams.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# IT Field Engineer (06.24 - 09.24)

UGG [TrainMore etc.] - www.urbangymgroup.com

- Provided on-site technical support for 10+ locations each week
- Managed IT asset inventory of 50+ items
- Collaborate cross-functionally to design a new user-friendly IT Service Desk web interface.

# L3 Software Engineer Support (2023 - 07.2024)

[confidential client] - B2B SaaS company

- Resolved 300+ software issues related to user authentication in B2B SaaS environment.
- Reproduced and documented 20+ software bugs in collaboration with development teams.
- Managed 50+ weekly tickets with average response time under 10 minutes.
- Created a web-based dashboard for visualizing authentication logs using React.

#### Owner & Full stack Developer (2021 - now)

Collabs Agency - www.collabsagency.com

- Developed and maintained 15+ responsive web applications using React, JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS3.
- Implemented RESTful API integrations for 5+ projects.
- Optimized website performance for 10+ client projects through code splitting and lazy loading.

#### **PROJECTS**

# 1. Framework Comparison Tool React

#### 2. Dorothy's Website Design

JavaScript, Framer Motion, Custom Components,

3. Kozijnen Frame Groep Groningen

JavaScript, Framer Motion, Custom Components

### **EDUCATION**

- Bachelor of ICT & Frontend Development (2020-2024) at Fontys Eindhoven
- Highschool of ICT & Business (2015-2019)
   at CNVM Galati

# **INTERNSHIPS**

# Frontend Developer Intern (02.22-06.22) Alumio Groningen - www.alumio.com

- Developed responsive designs and optimized code for 5+ different official pages.
- Collaborated with UX/UI team to implement user-centric interfaces.

# Software Engineer Intern (05.21- 10.21) TomTom - www.tomtom.com

- Contributed in 5 months to IT solutions that improved team SLA up to 99%.
- Actively participated in Agile sprints, daily meetings.
- Solved over 50+ tickets for internal collegues.

# SKILLS & PROFICIENCIES

- User authentication, SSL/TLS, OAuth, SAML,
   Web pen test (beginner), Threat intelligence
- JavaScript, HTML/CSS, React, Vue, Typescript, PWA, AJAX, SCSS
- Python, Bash, C++, C#
- Nmap, Git/GitHub, JIRA, MongoDB, Firebase, Active Directory
- Technical problem-solving, B2B & B2C stakeholder management, Agile collaboration

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- CompTIA Security+ (in progress, 2024)
- TryHackMe most tracks (2023 & 2024)
- Teamtreehouse Web Security (2023)
- Python & Bash automation course (2023)
- Agile & Scrum Course LinkedIn (2022)
- Responsive Web Design FreeCodeCamp (2021)